Welcome to the AvNav video on settings and layouts.
First, let’s clarify how AvNav distinguishes between these two categories.
Settings cover all the options that  allow you, as a user, to customise
the interface or, so to speak, the appearance of  AvNav. This starts with the size of the buttons
and the font size on buttons or in other parts of  the programme. It continues with the colours of
routes or tracks, spacing, how far the course  vector extends ahead, and so on and so forth.
So there is a vast array of customisation options.  Fortunately, the new version of AvNav offers
some simplifications. But more on that later. But what, then, are layouts? Layouts summarise how
You can arrange the widgets on the navigation page,  the route page and in the dashboard. Widgets are
predefined areas that can display a wide variety  of content and data alongside the actual map. You
may be familiar with widgets from your mobile  phone, for example for displaying weather data.
In the layout, you can specify which widgets  are displayed where and how they are configured.
That is the key difference between settings  and layouts. Layouts cover completely
customisable designs for the visibility of  data in AvNav. Settings control the basic
interface settings and also include layouts. Let’s now start with the layouts. To do this,
we’ll switch to the Layout page. As you can see, it’s structured
quite differently from the Settings page. Only the current layout can be edited at any one
time. This is clearly displayed in the  first line. At the moment, the layout
‘user.test’ is active. The list below  contains all the other saved layouts.
The prefix ‘user’ makes it clear that this is a  layout created by the user. Layouts prefixed with
‘System’ are preset and cannot be edited. You can now start editing the active
layout using the Edit button. A brief dialogue  box prompts you to enter a new name; otherwise,
clicking Edit will edit the current layout. The NavPage now appears slightly reduced in
the button bar on the right has also changed. If you click directly on a widget, you can
make changes. The most important option  is likely to be the “New Widget” line,
as this is where you can select an alternative  data display. Clicking on the current name
opens a drop-down list of all available widgets.  We’ll select COG as an example. If you now click
directly on “Update”, you’ll change the current  widget you selected earlier. Important: Use the
Before and After buttons to add a new  COG widget before or after the current
one. The active one will then remain unchanged. If you want to add a new widget from the start,
click in the empty area next to the  map and you will be guided through
the process of setting up a new widget. Further configuration options
for the edited widget are: Caption, which is the text displayed
alongside the value shown in the widget. Formatter. This is where the display of
the value is defined, along with the Unit  field. The format is usually already set.
Let’s take a closer look at this. We exit the  widget editing dialogue by clicking Cancel
and then click the Config button. Here you can specify two things: firstly, which
areas around the map should display  widgets at all, for example at the top
or bottom right. You can also specify under  which conditions the areas should display
widgets, e.g. only whilst anchor watchis active.  Please refer to the documentation for further
details. There are therefore very extensive
options for customising the layout of the widgets. And widgets aren’t just found on the navigation
page. It’s no coincidence that the  button bar includes a button for the
route editor. If you click this button,  you can customise the widgets that are to
be displayed specifically on the route page. But be careful. Don’t delete the route widget,
These are also edited via layouts. To do this,  go to the dashboards page via the main menu.
before on the NavPage, except that here the  display of values is enlarged and arranged